Daniel Sukoneck

linktr.ee/sukoneck linkedin.com/in/sukoneck

I am a creative devops practitioner whose passion for Web3, reliability, and improving user experiences rivals my passion for innovation, team building, and leadership. I have had great opportunities to lead large, constrained, and impactful projects with diverse teams to meet some of the most discerning needs.

Experience

Lead DevOps Engineer, Grand Canyon Education, 2019 - Present

Leader of a team of five engineers doing platform development and process automation using tools primarily from Hashi, AWS, and Azure for a leading higher education managed services provider.

- Developed a global AWS identity and account strategy. Wrote Terraform that managed all resources while also being modular and accessible enough for non-Terraform users to use. Built pipelines to enable self-service workflows. Created designs for the same in Azure
- Rebuilt and transitioned work-tracking boards, backlogs, and processes for multiple teams
- Managed architecture and feature development for ELK logging
- Led the initial phases of creating an IT program management office
- Built pipelines to support custom self-service Puppet architecture

Senior Cloud and Infrastructure Consultant, West Monroe Partners, 2014 - 2019

As a senior consultant at a business and technical consulting firm, I was responsible for executing technical and strategic infrastructure focused consulting engagements and promoting the growth and mentorship of my team.

- Helped a leading financial institution develop and execute their cloud strategy by creating a two-year migration roadmap. Developed architecture designs for 50+
 applications. Led 15 concurrent application teams in migrations
- Salvaged a behind-schedule data center migration for a healthcare analytics company. Built, planned, and led production cutover to new systems. Concurrently, carved out end-user systems from parent company and hired and trained a Sysadmin
- · Formal mentor of five junior resources with a focus on career progression, technical development, and professional growth
- Informed cloud strategies for multiple companies. Developed a tool to recommend app hosting models and report on risk and reward
- Provided actionable recommendations to improve the security posture of a leading healthcare insurer by evaluating their security tools
- Expanded team capabilities by spearheading proof of concepts for container orchestrators and server migration tools
- Awarded the west coast Consultant of the Year and selected for a mentorship program with executive leadership

Network and System Administrator, Safety Services Company, 2013 - 2014

The lead sysadmin for the nation's largest provider of safety training materials. Conprised of outbound sales centers spanning an enterprise of two main offices and five satellite locations with 500+ users in an Inc. 5000 fastest growing business environment.

- Trained and led a team of three desktop support technicians with a high end-user to technician ratio
- Managed NOC hardware relocation and data center rack reconstruction to improve disaster recovery
- Implemented VMware ESXi with vCenter and expanded SAN storage to accommodate growth while cutting costs
- · Administered Active Directory, Exchange, Dynamics, SharePoint, Lync, and user provisioning in a multiple domain network
- Orchestrated enterprise reimage of desktops to standardize and ease administration
- Instigated and managed rollout of roaming profiles for mobile users

Certs, etc.

- HashiCorp Certified: Terraform Associate Terraform
- Microsoft Certified Solutions Expert: Cloud Platform and Infrastructure MCSE
- Owner of and believer that everyone should feel.support

Education

Arizona State University, Graduated 2012

- Bachelor of Arts, Philosophy
- Certificate, Ethics
- Certificate, Symbolic Systems